We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
終わりなき旅の途中　立ち止まりそうな時
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
深いため息こぼす　僕らは
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
掴みかけてはまた離れていった
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
でも今はもう何も恐れることはない
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
心を繋ぐ強い絆は
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
けして解けはしないさ
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
探し続けて辿り着いた
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
この場所で Period に
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
悲しみ怒り 力に変えて
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
運命はすぐそばに
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
Shoot everyone except for Colonel Mustang!
マスタング大佐以外は　撃ってよし
By that,
マスタング大佐以外は
撃ってよしってことは
are you implying that the Madam may be shot as well?
夫人も撃っていいってことか
Those are words I wanted to hear, but...
聞きたかった言葉ではあるが…
I...
私は…
No, was my husband abandoned by his country?
いえ　主人は…
国に捨てられたのですか
Or perhaps, did he abandon me?
それとも
主人が　私を捨てたのですか
I can't say for sure.
分かりません
But you can rest assured that we'll insure your safety.
が…あなたの命は
我々が必ずお守りします
In order to prove after everything is over that what we are currently doing is not in the wrong.
すべて事が済んだときに
我々が間違っていなかったことを
証明していただくためにも
Reinforcements!
新手が来ます　急いで
Hurry!
Looks like you were saved.
命拾いしたな
Had we been soldiers from Briggs, you would have been dead.
オレたちがブリッグズ兵だったら
お前は死んでいた
What?!
何っ
Long time no see, Colonel.
大佐　お久しぶりです
Yeah. Good work.
ご苦労
What's Lieutenant General Grumman up to?
グラマン中将は
He's dealing with the aftermath of the train explosion.
列車事故の後始末を
Have you not mentioned to the Madam that her husband is currently missing?
大総統が行方不明の件は
夫人には話していないのですか
I haven't.
It would be hard to move around if she were to pass out from the shock.
気絶でもされては
移動が困難になる
They're gathering like ants.
うじゃうじゃ来てますよ
You're too popular, Colonel.
モテモテですね　大佐
You're telling me...
まったくだ
You still haven't taken care of them?!
まだ片づかんのか
What are they doing?!
何をやっている
There are only five enemies!
たかだか　五人だぞ
They've increased in numbers!
敵勢力が増加
Apparently, they're currently at least the size of a platoon!
少なくとも　一個小隊はいるもよう
Our casualties?
こちらの損害は
59 injured, no deaths, sir!
負傷５９　死亡０です
None?
ゼロ
Damn them...
くそっ　大丈夫か
Are you alright?!
Just barely...
なんとか…
The Flame Alchemist is the one who was devastating in Ishbal, right?
焔の錬金術師って　あれだろ
イシュヴァール戦で
ものすごかったって
Am I the only one who feels like he's not as powerful as the rumors say?
なんか　意外と大したことないような…
Agreed.
だよなぁ　さっきからしょぼい爆炎ばっかで
All I've been seeing from him are tiny explosion flames...
Jess! Parkie!
ジェス　パーキー
Dammit! He got my eardrum!
くそっ　鼓膜やられた
What are the casualties?!
損害は
5 injured, no deaths!
負傷５　死亡０
We're lucky that none were killed.
死人が出なかったのはラッキーだ
Both the hero of Ishbal and the "Hawk's Eye" are against us.
「イシュヴァールの英雄」に
「鷹の目」もいるんだぞ
It's strange that none of our men have died.
死人が出ない方が　おかしい
It couldn't be...!
まさか
They really are!
間違いない…ヤツら…
They're...!
Going easy on us?!
手を抜いているだと
Yes.
はい
There are quite a few casualties, but none have been killed so far.
負傷者は多いですが
ここまで　死者０
Even the ones who were sniped were not hit in critical spots.
狙撃された者も
すべて急所を外されています
なっ…なめおって…
Mocking us like that...!
Have the Demetri Squad and Kim Squad deployed as well!
ディミトリ隊とキム隊も出せ
Hurry up and make a stack of the corpses of Mustang's men right here!
とっとと　マスタングの部下の死体を
ここに積み上げろ
They still haven't captured Mustang?
まだマスタングは捕まらんのか
What in the world is Brigadier General Clemin doing?!
何をやっとるんだ　クレミン准将は
Apparently, they're only chipping at our forces without killing any of them.
ヤツらはこちらの兵を殺さずに
戦力だけ　そいでいるとか…
There's no way they can keep up something that crafty for so long.
そんな器用なまねが続くわけなかろう
Colonel Mustang sure is soft.
マスタング大佐も甘いですな
Seriously.
まったくだ
What the hell is he thinking?
何を考えているのか
And the Central Army who can't even defeat him are even more inexperienced.
それを倒せぬ中央軍も
甘ったるいことこのうえない
It's almost like child's play.
まるで子供の遊びです
What did you say?
なんだと
I've heard that headquarters was almost completely frozen by a single traitor.
聞けば以前にも  たった一人の反逆者に
司令部を氷づけにされかかったとか
Central has never been attacked by a large force since the country was established.
そもそも　建国以来　セントラルは
大きな敵に攻められたことがない
This inexperience is its greatest weakness.
この経験のなさこそが弱点
Good on the offensive, but absolutely terrible on the defensive.
攻撃はうまくても　防御がド下手
What do you think?
どうです　中央軍を
How about you put me in charge of the Central Army for a bit?
少し私に預けてみませんか
Don't get too cocky, Armstrong!
調子に乗るなよ  アームストロング
Do you think you're here right now because of your own ability?
自分が実力で
この場にいると思っているのか
You're only here so that we can control you.
貴様はここに拘束されているだけだ
We're aware that you and the soldiers at Briggs have a strong bond.
ブリッグズ兵と貴様のつながりが
強いのは知っている
The fact that you're here is a powerful shackle on their wrists to prevent them from 		opposing us.
それゆえに
貴様がここにいることが
ブリッグズ兵に反抗させないための
強力な枷となる
You guys don't know anything about us!
あなた方は我々の何も分かっちゃいない
I've told them beforehand to abandon me in the event of an emergency.
ヤツらには有事の際には
私を見捨てろと言い含めてある
The law of Briggs is "Survival of the Fittest".
ブリッグズの掟は　「弱肉強食」
Even if I were to die here, they'd only shrug it off and say it happened because I was 	too weak.
たとえ　私がここで
くたばったとしても
それは私が弱かっただけのこととして
切り捨て
They're a group that will move on without flinching.
ひるまず　動くことのできる集団
That's what it means to be a soldier at Briggs.
それがブリッグズ兵だ
Don't you dare speak of the soldiers I raised without actually knowing them!
上っ面で　私が育てた兵を語るな
They're currently exchanging fire with Colonel Mustang and the crew in the industrial area in the west district.
西区工場地帯で
マスタング大佐が交戦中
A lot of soldiers were sent to that area.
多くの兵がそちらに割かれている
Let's do this.
出るぞ
Time to say goodbye to this cellar.
この穴蔵とも　おさらばだ
Give those cowards at Central a good bite in the windpipe!
セントラルの腰抜けどもの
のど笛にかみついてやれ
See? Here they come.
ほら来たぞ
Veterans who can put up a fight against the giant bears at Briggs.
ブリッグズ山の巨大熊と
タメを張れる猛者どもだ
I wonder who'd win; them or those proud dolls of yours?
あなた方自慢の人形と
どちらが強いかな
Dammit!
くそっ
New forces?!
新勢力
That's ridiculous!
バカな　どこからわいた
Where did they come from?!
それが町の中から突然…
They just suddenly appeared from within the city!
They're not magicians, dammit!
そんな魔法みたいなことがあるか
You men go too!
お前たちも行け
Enemy numbers?
敵の数は
Unconfirmed, sir!
不明です
But from their equipment, we can assume that they're from the north!
ですが　装備から見るに
北の兵ではないかと
Briggs...?
ブリッグズか
From the Armstrong's mansion?
アームストロング家の中
Yeah.
We snuck soldiers and weapons into the basement while the mansion was being repaired.
屋敷の修理に紛れて
兵と武器を地下に運び入れていた
How big is the place, exactly?
どんだけでかいんですか　その家
Charlie!
チャーリー　弾くれ
Give me some ammo!
Sorry, we're out too.
すまんが　こっちも弾切れだ
This is bad...
参ったなぁ…
What's taking the supply squad so long?
補給部隊はまだ来ねぇのか
Don't tell me they were captured...
まさか　捕まったんじゃ…
If things get really bad, desert me and run.
お前たち　もしものときは
私を置いて逃げろよ
Roger that!
了解
Isn't this where you're supposed to say, "I'll follow you to the depths of hell"?
そこは 「最後までお供します」
じゃないのかね
Last thing I want to do is to commit double suicide with a guy.
男と心中なんて　まっぴらです
I've got a wife waiting for me at home, too.
家でカミさんが待ってるしな
Oh...
...really?
そうかい
Th-They've started using less bullets on us.
ヤ…ヤツら
銃による反撃が
ほとんどなくなってきました
I'm assuming they're just about out of ammo.
そろそろ弾切れでしょう
Okay, let's wrap this up!
よし　畳み込むぞ
Gather everyone that's left!
残ってるヤツらを集めろ
Hey, Riza!
やっほい　リザ
You're late, Rebecca!
レベッカ　遅刻よ
My bad, my bad!
悪い悪い　そんなお待ちかねの
So for those of you who waited so patiently...
あなたたちに
I've got a few gifts to hand out!
すてきなプレゼント
Amazing...
すげぇ…
Not just ammo, but all this too?!
弾だけじゃなくて
こんなもんまで
Nice, Rebecca! I love you!
いいぞ　レベッカ　愛してる
Shut up!
うっさい
Men without money have no right to hit on me!
金のない男は私を口説くな
Here.
どうぞ
Yeah. Thanks.
すまない
It's been a while, Colonel Mustang.
お久しぶりです　マスタング大佐
Second Lieutenant Maria Ross,
returning without permission, sir!
マリア·ロス少尉
ただいま　勝手に帰還しました
Why aren't they rushing in?
なんで　あいつら
突っ込んでこないの
They can't approach carelessly because we have the Flame Alchemist on our side!
こっちに  焔の錬金術師がいるから
うかつに近づけないんです
But the Colonel can't go all out because we're in the middle of the city.
でも　大佐も町なかだから
派手に炎を出せなくて…
あらまっ　セントラルのいい男
Oh my.
I came to Central to find hot guys, but it seems like they're all nothing but cowards!
つかまえに来たのに
腰抜けばっかりねっ
Shit!
くそっ
Tear-gas grenades from Xing,
シンの国の催涙弾よ
トウガラシ　増量
packed with red peppers!
You got all of these from Xing?!
もしかして　これ
全部　シンで仕入れたのか
I hadn't heard that you were a part of the mission.
君が作戦に加わっているとは
聞いていなかった
You procured all these weapons by yourself?
これほど大量の武器を
君一人で調達したのか
Or was it on someone else's orders...
それとも　誰かの指示で…
Would you like to speak with him?
話しますか　本人と
We're good to go!
オッケーです
Here.
どうぞ
Some important person from Xing, perhaps?
シンのお偉いさんか
This is Roy Mustang, a colonel in the state military.
国軍大佐　ロイ·マスタングです
I'm terribly grateful for-
この度は誠に…
What are you acting all polite for?
かしこまっちゃって　まあ
Come on, Colonel. Just chat like we always used to.
いつもの調子でいきましょうや
大佐
Eighty years at your service.
愛されて８０年
Anything from underwear elastics to armored vehicles.
パンツのゴムから装甲車まで
Just one call, and we'll have it delivered to you. Anytime, anywhere.
電話一本で
いつでもどこでもお届け参上
Your friendly neighborhood Havoc General Store!
あなたの町のハボック雑貨店
Havoc!
ハボック
So, where's the money?
で　お支払いは
I'll pay up after I'm successful.
出世払いだ　ツケとけ
Keep it on my tab.
There's smoke rising from the city.
町に煙が上がっているぞ
I can faintly hear the sound of an alarm, also.
かすかに警報も聞こえる
Looks like the Colonel and the men from Briggs have begun to make their move.
大佐とブリッグズの連中が
動きだしたみたいだな
Central must be in a state of pandemonium right now.
今ごろ　セントラルは大混乱だ
Guess it's time to go.
そろそろ行くか
Yeah.
We've prepared the counter for the Nationwide Transmutation Circle,
国土錬成陣のカウンターは
仕込んであるが
but it wouldn't hurt to stop it before it's activated.
元から発動させないに
こしたことはない
He's basically just like how he was in the flask, but bigger.
あいつはしょせん  フラスコの中身が
でかくなっただけだ
If you destroy his container, he should perish.
入れ物を壊せば死ぬだろう
We'll... also be able to free the souls of the ones that are bound inside him.
あいつの…
中に縛られている人々の魂も
解放してあげられる
But how do we get to him?
けど　どうやって
そいつのとこまで行くんだ
We're going to use the underground path I took with May in the past.
以前　メイとともに入った
地下道を使う
There are tons of deadly chimera, but we should be able to get through with our current party.
凶悪な合成獣が山ほどいるが
このメンツならいけるだろう
You stay here, Heinkel.
ハインケルは留守を頼む
Okay.
すまんな
Sorry about this.
Not your fault.
気にするな
Doctor Marcoh, make sure the military doesn't find you.
マルコーさんは軍の連中に見つかんなよ
Yoki!
ヨキ　お前も留守番してろ
You wait here too.
G-Gladly.
よ…喜んで
Al.
アル
Yeah, Brother?
何　兄さん
I'm going to go out for a sec to beat the hell out of a certain bearded nuisance.
ちょっくら行って　地下のヒゲ野郎
ぶっとばしてくるから
Be careful.
気をつけてね
You got it.
It seems like there's something going on...
何やら　町が騒がしいですね
I'd hurry if I were you.
急いだ方がいいよ
Father should be revealing the secret to immortality soon.
もうすぐお父様が見せてくれるはずだ
不老不死の秘密をね
分かってます
I know that!
We're going to form a cordon here!
ここに非常線を張る
Don't let Mustang's group or the Briggs soldiers past the line!
マスタング隊もブリッグズ兵も
一歩も通すな
Have your soldiers retreat immediately!
すぐに兵を引き揚げさせろ
You all are the ones who took away my right to command Briggs.
ブリッグズの指揮権を
私から奪ったのはそっちだろう
You...!
貴様
Do you think you're getting away with this?!
タダで済むと思っているのか
Let me redirect that question right back to you.
そちらこそ
タダで済むと思っているのか
You've heard from that 'Father' guy, haven't you?
お父様とやらに
聞いているのだろう
What you're going to sacrifice and what you're going to gain.
何を犠牲にして
何を得ようとしているのか
Yes, of course.
聞いているとも
We the chosen ones will climb to a new height,
我ら選ばれた者たちが
更なる高みへ上り
and Amestris will change the world!
このアメストリスが世界を変える
Change must be accompanied by pain.
変化するために痛みを伴うのは
しかたのないことだ
Is it really that hard to understand?!
それがなぜ分からぬ
You pigs are beyond all hope.
もうダメだな　貴様らは
何っ
What?
You cowards who hide in the rear lines and glance over the battlefield...
ぬくぬくと
安全地帯から戦場を眺める
貴様らのような者が
...like to pass off 'pain' as if it were something noble, and proceed to make use of it.
痛みとかいうものを
さも崇高であるかのように
仕立て上げ利用する
Are you planning to turn traitor?!
反逆者になる気か
I don't know about that.
どうかな
I may have become a heroine instead, after everything's over.
事が終わったときには
英雄になっているかもしれんぞ
However...!
ただし
I'm not as soft as the hero of Ishbal.
私はイシュヴァールの英雄ほど
甘ったるくはない
W-Wait!
待て
What?!
何っ
Sir!
閣下
Major Armstrong!
アームストロング少佐
Sergeant Brosh.
ブロッシュ軍曹
Don't you have the day off today?
今日は休みではなかったか
I rushed here after seeing smoke from my window.
家から煙が見えたので
What happened?
何があったんですか
Colonel Mustang and his former men are holding the Führer President's wife hostage,
マスタング大佐と
その元部下たちが
大総統夫人を人質に取って
and are currently on the run in the city.
市内を逃走中だ
What?
That coward!
おのれ　卑怯な
First, he kills the innocent Second Lieutenant Ross, and now he kidnaps the Madam?
無実のロス少尉を殺しておいて
今度は　夫人を…
He's a devil in the shape of a human!
人の皮をかぶった悪魔め
Major!
少佐
In the meeting room at headquarters, Major General Armstrong killed Lieutenant General 	Gardner by...
司令部会議室で
アームストロング少将が
ガードナー中将を…
Shot to death?!
射殺
Okay.
Seems like things are moving faster than I'd imagined.
想像より
早く事が進んでおるな
I need to find the young master soon.
早く若を捜さねば　とはいえ
However, I can't sense him because the giant flow of energy underground is interfering...
気配で追おうにも　地下の
巨大な気の流れが邪魔で…
Huh?
はて
It feels like the energy underground has spread more so than yesterday...
先日よりも　地下の気配が
広がっておるような…
This won't do.
ダメだ　こりゃ
The soldiers are gathered right in front of it, and we can't approach.
ちょうど　軍の集合場所になってて
近づけそうにない
It'll be a bit tough to force our way through.
強行突破するには
ちょっと厳しいな
There's another entrance!
あるぞ　ほかにも入り口が
Research Laboratory 3!
第三研究所だ
Al and the Colonel have infiltrated there before and ended up fighting against the 	Homunculi!
前にアルと大佐が侵入して
人造人間と戦ってる
Three guards, huh?
入り口の警備は３人だな
Okay, let's do this.
どれ  一丁やるか
いや　こういうときこそ
No no, this is the time for me to use my position.
オレの肩書の使いどころだろ
Soldiers!
憲兵さん
I'm Edward Elric, a State Alchemist!
国家錬金術師の
エドワード·エルリックです
Huh?
A State Alchemist, sir?!
国家錬金術師殿
助けてください
Please, help me!
I'm being chased by Scar!
スカーに追われてるんです
He's a wanted man!
指名手配の男だ
Freeze!
動くな
You're terrible.
お前　ひどいねぇ
うっせぇ　行くぞ
Shut up, let's go.
Yeah yeah, coming through.
はい　ちょっとごめんよ
I think it was around here...
確か　この辺りに…
Here it is!
あった
Should we split up?
二手に分かれるか
Yeah.
だな
I'll go this way.
オレはこっち
Edward and Scar go the other way.
エドワードとスカーはそっちな
What?!
Why do I have to go with him?!
なんでオレがこいつと
If you try to distribute strength alchemy-wise, this would be best.
錬成の力配分でいったら　こうだろ
Besides, when the enemy sealed alchemy,
それに　あいつが
錬金術封じの技を使ったとき
Scar was able to use it but you couldn't do anything, right?
スカーは使えたけど
お前は無力だったんだろ
Okay, then these two should go together.
じゃあ
こいつらセットで決まりな
What about the rest of us?
ほかはどうする
I'm not your average Joe, so I'll be fine on my own.
オレは規格外だから
一人で大丈夫だ
But, well...
だが　まあ…
I guess I'll take this lady from Xing as my bodyguard.
せっかくだから　シンのお嬢さんに
ボディーガードになってもらおうか
Okay, so if you see him,
それじゃあ　あいつを見つけたら
全力で壊す方向で
give it your all to destroy him.
Roger!
了解
Will you guys really be all right with just the two of you?
ほんとに　二人だけで大丈夫か
Of course.
大丈夫　大丈夫
Besides, old men prefer being alone with young women.
おっさんは若い娘さんと
二人だけの方がうれしいの
What a pervert.
スケベおやじめ
Let's go already.
行こ行こ
You need to find the Prince of Xing, right?
君　シンの皇子を
捜さなきゃいけないんだろ
Go.
行きなさい
Er, but...
いや　しかし…
Don't worry about us.
我々のことは気にするな
He means a lot to you, doesn't he?
大事な人なんだろ
Thank you.
ありがとう…ございます
Seriously, what pathetic fools!
まったく　情けない連中だ
They can't even fight properly against those monkeys from Briggs?!
ブリッグズの山猿どもに
手も足も出んとは
Please, wait!
お待ちください
We haven't finished experimenting with the soul attachment process yet!
複数体の魂の定着実験はまだ…
黙れ　今使わんでいつ使う
Shut it!
When would be a better time to use them than now?!
We've created so many philosopher's stones for situations like this!
こういうときのためにさんざん作った
賢者の石ではないか
Now, move!
さあ　動け
Devour those traitors!
反逆者どもを食らい尽くせ
The promise we never made
交わしたはずのない約束が
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
今日も
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
僕らの未来を奪おうとする
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
欲しがっていたものを手にしても
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
素直に
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
うまく笑えないのはなぜだろう
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
あふれる涙は　弱さや後悔じゃない
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
イタミが生んだカケラで
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
どんな瞬間だって運命だって
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
ひとつだけ確かなものがあると知った
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
限界だって困難だって
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
あきらめたくないよ
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
このまま離さないで
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
かたく握りしめた　君の右手のぬくもり
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
ここにあるから
Koko ni arukara
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
かつて　人に宿りし魂が
Souls that once dwelled inside humans now dwell inside puppets and are lurching forth.
今　人形に宿り　闊歩する
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
Although their appearances are deformed, their souls are indeed human.
姿形は　異形なれども
その魂は　まさしく人間
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第５１話　『不死の軍団』
Episode 51, The Immortal Legion.
倒すべきか　倒さざるべきか
Should they be defeated, or should they be spared?